

+61 424 958 951 | E: amitshrestha37@gmail.com

5/12-16 Belmore St, Burwood, NSW 2134

amitshrestha.info.np | linkedin.com/in/mrtordoide | twitter.com/mrtordoide

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Enthusiastic, passionate, hardworking and motivated IT graduate with major in Mobile and Web Application Development, recently graduated from Victoria University, Sydney with expert understanding of various web programming languages. Developed and maintained websites for a number of clients while ensuring high availability web hosting and maintenance of sites.

SOFT SKILLS

- Curious
- Self-motivated
- Powerful negotiator
- Extremely organized
- Can-do attitude

- Punctual
- Quick learner
- Good communication and organizational skills

HARD SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, PHP, HTML5/CSS3, Java and more.
- Frameworks/CMS: Bootstrap, WordPress, Laravel, ExpressJS, ReactJS, JQuery and more.
- Tools & Technologies: Linux/Windows/MacOS, Apache, Nginx, NodeJS, Git, Bash, APIs, WHM/cPanel, Windows Server, Office 365, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform, MySQL, FTP and more.

WORK HISTORY

WEB DEVELOPER INTERN

07/2020 to CURRENT

111iT Solutions Pty. Ltd. | Sydney, NSW

- Build front-end interfaces with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript including the usage of different frameworks.
- Apply knowledge of JavaScript and PHP's Object-Oriented Programming techniques to fulfill client requirements.
- Design and develop responsive web applications, compatible with top browsers, including Firefox, Chrome, Opera, Safari and others.
- Usage of various project management and communication tools like
 Trello, Slack and version control tools like Git with GitHub and GitLab.

IHELPER

10/2018 to 07/2020

Victoria University, VU Sydney Campus | Sydney, NSW

- Provided IT support to the VU Sydney staffs and Students as well.
- Developed and maintained team web portal to manage and track tasks of team members.
- Assisted students as well as teachers at VUS with Office 365, MyVU

- Portal trouble shootings, Printings and other application software.
- Nominated by Victoria University Student Leadership Awards in Studentas-Staff Award category.

STUDENT MENTOR TEAM LEADER

07/2018 to 07/2020

Victoria University, VU Sydney Campus | Sydney, NSW

- Help new students to transition through their first days at University by sharing own knowledge and experiences.
- Assist new as well as old students in orientation sessions and enrollment.
- Supervised Student Mentors in different sections to provide assistance during enrolment and solve general student inquiry.

ACADEMIC TUTOR (NETWORKING), BACHELOR OF IT

07/2018 to 07/2020

Victoria University, VU Sydney Campus | Sydney, NSW

- Provided early intervention assistance to struggling students.
- Complete support for students unable to attend regular classes.
- Offered complete instructional support for students unable to attend regular classes.

EDUCATION

Bachelor | Information Technology

08/2019

Victoria University, VU Sydney Campus, Sydney, NSW

 Major in Mobile and Web Application Development and Minor in Network Management (Average grade of "HD")

High School Certificate | Science with Computer Science National School of Science, Kathmandu, Nepal

School Leaving Certificate

Daisy English Boarding Secondary School, Chitwan, Nepal

TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS

- Learning the JavaScript Language. <u>View: https://bit.ly/3201iVo</u>
- Micro Course Critical Thinking and Problem Solving. <u>View:</u> <u>http://bit.ly/32yckgx</u>
- Developing IoT Solutions using Azure and Windows 10 training organised by Microsoft Innovation Center, Nepal. <u>View:</u> https://goo.gl/v7WQFB
- Science and Robotics Workshop 2016 organized by Kalinga Science Centre, View: http://bit.ly/2Ssu4Fk